Alexander W. Tickle

4824 Muir Ave, San Diego, CA 92107 | (619) 736-1039 | alexander.tickle@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-tickle/ | Portfolio: https://alextickle.github.io/

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with strong analytical skills dedicated to building and optimizing creative web applications that provide intuitive user experiences. Strong background in project management from previous professional experience in software localization and wildlife conservation.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, Java, Python, SQL, CSS, HTML

Frameworks/Libraries – React, Angular, Express, jQuery, JUnit, Redux, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Radium, Handlebars, Jest **Other-** Eclipse, Maven, IDLE, gulp, agile development, REST API's

WORK EXPERIENCE

MJD Interactive | San Diego, CA

June 2017 – September 2017

Web Development Intern

- 50+ pull requests in two major client engagements, American Girl Doll (AG) and The Container Store (TCS)
- AG: implemented bug fixes, built front end features, and provided browser support
- TCS: built GraphQL backend for client web application and integrated data into React frontend using React Apollo
- Extensive use of Pivotal Tracker (agile project management platform, similar to JIRA)

CETRA Language Solutions | San Diego, CA

April 2016 - March 2017

Project Manager

- Managed translation projects from client handoff to final delivery for market research firms
- Communicated directly with clients and vendors to determine project scope, report on progress, and adapt to changes

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology (MPI-EVA)} & | Leipzig, Germany \\ \end{tabular} \label{eq:maxplanck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology (MPI-EVA)} | Leipzig, Germany \\ \end{tabular}$

August 2013 – December 2015

Field Site Manager

- Managed temporary field site for chimpanzee research in GEPRENAF zone of northern Côte d'Ivoire as part of MPI-EVA's Pan African Program (comparative study of chimpanzees at 30+ field sites across Africa)
- Responsible for all data collection, logistics, team management, and accounting for entire 15-month study
- Extensive use of handheld GPS, GIS software, and Excel
- Coauthored "Chimpanzee accumulative stone throwing" (manuscript published in Scientific Reports, https://www.nature.com/articles/srep22219)

PROJECTS

All source code available on GitHub: https://github.com/alextickle

breakfast-club-graphql-redux - React app built by team Empty String as final project at LEARN Academy, helps users organize weekly breakfast meetups. Rewritten with GraphQL and React-Apollo/Redux frontend.

zoohack – Node app built by team Local Rangers during Zoohackathon 2017, won first prize. SMS system to allow Costa Ricans to contribute data to researchers protecting endangered birds in areas with poor telecom infrastructure.

java_III_InventoryApp – Java inventory management application with both GUI and command line views to demonstrate MVC architecture. GUI built using Swing components. Data persisted into database using JDBC and PostgreSQL. Built in Eclipse.

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy | San Diego, CA

March 2017 - June 2017

 $Java Script \ full \ stack \ Java Script \ web \ development \ boot \ camp-Node, Express, \ React, \ Postgre SQL$

UC San Diego Extension | San Diego, CA

July 2016 – September 2017

Java Programming Certificate Program (GPA = 4.0/4.0)

University of Pennsylvania | Philadelphia, PA

2009 -2013

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA = 3.75/4.0)